Inventory of the Daughters of the American Colonists, William Clayton Chapter (Laramie, Wyo.) records, 1912-1976
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Daughters of the American Colonists, William Clayton Chapter (Laramie, Wyo.) records
1912-1976
1950-1976
Daughters of the American Colonists, William Clayton Chapter (Laramie, Wyo.)
00314
1 cubic ft. (2 document boxes, 1 shoe box)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
The collection contains material compiled by members and officers of the Daughters of the American Colonists with the purpose of commemorating the American colonists and researching the members’ family genealogy.
History of the Daughters of the American Colonists, William Clayton Chapter (Laramie, Wyo.)
The William Clayton Chapter of the National Society of the Daughters of the American Colonists was founded in Laramie, Wyoming, in 1953 with the purpose of commemorating the American colonists and researching the members’ family genealogy. Members were expected to demonstrate that they had at least one ancestor who resided in the country before the creation of the United States of America.
Scope and Content
The collection contains material compiled by members and officers of the Daughters of the American Colonists. Four scrapbooks document club activities through newspaper clippings, membership lists, photographs, publications, and copies of papers and reports written by members. The research material includes both Wyoming information (church records, county records, territorial records) and family genealogies which cover many parts of the country.
The index cards in Series III carry dates of admission from the 1920s through the early 1930s. The names are of infants and small children primarily in the Laramie area, but it is not clear to what the children are being admitted.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no other known archival collections created by the Daughters of the American Colonists, William Clayton Chapter (Laramie, Wyo.) at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
The Daughters of the American Colonists records were given to the American Heritage Center in several accretions beginning in 1953 and continuing through 1998. The original donor was Mrs. Oviatt Spieckerman.
Access Terms
McIntosh, Robert.; Felton, Alice Burt.; Brookes, Theophilus James, 1834-1910.;; Churches--Wyoming--Laramie.; Genealogy.; Albany County (Wyo.); Albany County (Wyo.)--Genealogy.; Cheyenne (Wyo.); Laramie (Wyo.); Laramie (Wyo.)--Genealogy.; Fort Bridger (Wyo.); Fort Sanders (Wyo.); Routt County (Colo.);; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
Social Life and Customs; Clubs and Societies; Military; Wyoming
Container List
- Organizational Records, 1950-1976; Series I.; 0.45 cubic ft. (1 document box)
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title, chronologically within that division. Consists largely of scrapbooks documenting the activities of the organization. Also included is a small amount of correspondence.
  - Correspondence, 1950-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1953-1964 (Box 1, Folders 2-3)
  - Scrapbook, 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folders 4-6)
  - Scrapbook – Public Relations Committee, 1960-1968 (Box 1, Folders 7-8)
  - Scrapbook – Public Relations Committee, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook – Miscellaneous Loose Material, 1964-1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Research Material, 1912-1972; Series II.; 0.45 cubic ft. (1 document box)
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title. Contains material collected and contributed by members to assist in genealogical research, including transcripts of county records (primarily Albany County, Wyoming), transcripts of church records (primarily Cheyenne and Laramie, Wyoming), and genealogies of various members’ families.
  - Church Records:
    - Brookes (Rev. Theophilus James) Private Register, 1886-1909, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Listing births and marriages in Lyons, Council Bluffs, and Mapleton, Iowa; Clinton, Neosho, and Rich Hill, Missouri; El Reno, Oklahoma Territory; and surrounding areas. Includes biographical information on Brookes.
    - Cheyenne, First Presbyterian Church, 1870-1912, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Cheyenne Methodist Church, 1868-1901, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Laramie, 1869-1918, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Laramie Churches, Early Records, 1871-1909, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Laramie, First Baptist Church, 1870-1970, 1953, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Laramie, St. Matthew’s Cathedral, 1887-1911, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Laramie, St. Matthew’s Cathedral, Printed Material, 1934-1943 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Family Records:
    - Bevans, Finfrock, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Bigham, Bingham, Downey, Page, Rasnake, Sturtevant, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Converse, Beach, Hemingway, 1912-1913, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Forman (George), 1830-1889, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Hayes, Cinnamon, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Hodges, 1820-1939, circa 1890s-1939, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Includes original genealogical record pages torn from Bible of David Hodges.
    - Hollenbeck, Tomkins, Wolcott, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Horner, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Lewis, Cadwallader, circa 1962 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Loomis (John), 1622-1688, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Oviatt, Hallam, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Spieckermann, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Starrett. Briggs, Cleland, Deal, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Wood, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Fort Bridger Cemetery Records, 1865-1933, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Laramie – Early Day Events in Laramie, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Manuscript by May Baird Campbell
  - Wyoming County Records (Albany) – Marriage License Records, 1869-1880, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Wyoming County Records (Albany) – Register of Births, 1899-1902, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Wyoming County Records (Albany) – Register of Births and Deaths, 1901-1918, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Wyoming County Records (Albany) – Register of Deaths, 1899-1908, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Wyoming Territory Records – Mortality Schedules, 1880, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Admission Cards, circa 1920s-circa 1930s; Series III.; 0.3 cubic ft. (1 shoe box)
  Arranged alphabetically by name. Index cards listing names of infants and small children, dates of birth, dates of “admission,” age, names of parents, and address.
  - Index cards (3x5”) listing name, birth date, age, parents, address, date of admission, circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Box 3)